{
  "title": "3.5",
  "definitions": {
    "INTERCEPT": {
      "word": "INTERCEPT",
      "phonetic": "(in-tÔøΩr-sept')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to cut off, interrupt the course of </p><p> </p><p>To INTERCEPT something is to stop or catch it on its way from one place to another. In football, when someone INTERCEPTS a pass, he catches it before it reaches the person for whom it was intended. To INTERCEPT a message is to overhear or see it while it is going from the sender to the receiver. </p><p>“We tried to INTERCEPT the enemy’s planes before they reached their targets.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: INTERCEPTION, n.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">inter-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "MEDDLE": {
      "word": "MEDDLE",
      "phonetic": "(med'-1)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to interfere, butt in </p><p>To MEDDLE is to involve yourself in something without being asked or without having the right. </p><p>“People would get angry with him because he liked to MEDDLE in their private business.” </p><p>“Please don’t MEDDLE with these papers. They’re too important.” </p><p>“They accused him of MEDDLING, but he said he had every right to know what was going on.” </p><p>Usage: MEDDLE is usually followed by <i class=“def-ital\">with</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">in</i>.</p>"
    },
    "MISGIVING": {
      "word": "MISGIVING",
      "phonetic": "(mis-giv'-ing)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a doubt, suspicion </p><p>To have MISGIVINGS about something is to feel doubt or suspicion about it, to be unsure that it is right or that it will work. </p><p>“I had MISGIVINGS about this project from the start. I’m not surprised that it has failed completely.” </p><p>“My mind was full of MISGIVINGS. I wasn’t sure I wanted to do this at all.” </p><p>“She had MISGIVINGS about hiring Bob. He didn’t look honest to her.” </p><p>Usage: MISGIVING is usually used in the plural, MISGIVINGS.</p>"
    },
    "MUTE": {
      "word": "MUTE",
      "phonetic": "(myUt)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">silent, speechless, unable to speak </p><p>A MUTE is someone who is unable to speak, usually because he was born deaf and has never heard spoken sounds. As an adjective, MUTE means <i class=“def-ital\">silent</i>, <i class=“def-ital\">not talking</i>. A person can be MUTE not only because he can’t speak, but because he doesn’t choose to speak. </p><p>“He remained MUTE while his mother scolded him.” </p><p>“She took the food with MUTE thanks.” </p><p>MUTE is also a verb which means “to muffle or soften the sound of.” </p><p>“He MUTED the trumpet.”</p>"
    },
    "NEGOTIATE": {
      "word": "NEGOTIATE",
      "phonetic": "(ni-gO'-shE-At)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to bargain, try to come to an agreement </p><p>NEGOTIATE is especially used in business, law, and diplomacy. It can mean to <i class=“def-ital\">carry out</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">conduct</i>. </p><p>“She NEGOTIATED an important business deal.” </p><p>Usually, though, its meaning is “to arrange for or settle by bargaining or discussion.” </p><p>“The union NEGOTIATED a new contract.” </p><p>“He NEGOTIATED a peace treaty between the enemies.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: NEGOTIATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "PRECAUTION": {
      "word": "PRECAUTION",
      "phonetic": "(pri-ko'-sh:;,,n)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a safeguard; foresight </p><p> <i class=“def-ital\">Caution</i> is <i class=“def-ital\">care</i>, <i class=“def-ital\">carefulness</i>. PRECAUTION is care taken ahead of time in order to avoid something bad happening. </p><p>“He told them to use PRECAUTION when they were sailing in rough seas.” </p><p>A PRECAUTION is an act of caution done ahead of time. </p><p>“She took an umbrella as a PRECAUTION in case it rained later.” </p><p>“You must take every PRECAUTION before clearing the mine field.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: PRECAUTIONARY, adj.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">pre-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "REFORM": {
      "word": "REFORM",
      "phonetic": "(ri-form')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to correct, improve, change for the better </p><p>REFORM basically means “to form something over again.”  Usually REFORM has the sense of changing something for the better by removing faults or evil ways. </p><p>“The business promised to REFORM its sales practices so that it wouldn’t mislead people.” </p><p>“The kindly teacher managed to REFORM the rough boys by his good example.” </p><p>When someone REFORMS,he corrects bad habits and improves his character. </p><p>“I used to be an alcoholic,but I’ve REFORMED and now I never take a drink.” </p><p>A REFORM school or REFORMATORY is a place which tries to REFORM children who have broken the law. </p><p>Other forms of the word: REFORMATION, n. REFORMATORY,n.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">re-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "RESUME": {
      "word": "RESUME",
      "phonetic": "(ri-zUm')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to begin again, start anew </p><p>To RESUME something is to take it up again after having stopped for a time. </p><p>“After a year of rest she RESUMED working.” </p><p>“He came back twenty minutes later and RESUMED the story exactly where he had left off.” </p><p>“I RESUMED playing tennis when the doctor said I should get more exercise.” </p><p>When something RESUMES it starts over again. </p><p>“The show RESUMED after the commercial.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: RESUMPTION,n.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">re-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "SERVICEABLE": {
      "word": "SERVICEABLE",
      "phonetic": "(ser'-vis-ÔøΩb:;,I)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">useful, helpful, able to be used, fit for use </p><p>SERVICEABLE means “able to be of SERVICE,” <i class=“def-ital\">useful</i>.  If you make something SERVICEABLE, you fix it so that it can be used. </p><p>“His shoes were repaired so that they were SERVICEABLE for everyday use.” </p><p>SERVICEABLE often suggests that something is good enough for use without being outstanding. A SERVICEABLE object may not be the best or newest, but it will do the job. </p><p>“The pot was dented,but it was SERVICEABLE.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: SERVE, v. SERVICE, n.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-able</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "TRANQUIL": {
      "word": "TRANQUIL",
      "phonetic": "(trang'-kwÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">peaceful,calm,serene, unruffled </p><p>TRANQUIL means “free from anything that bothers or excites,” peaceful. </p><p>“They live in a TRANQUIL little village, far from the noise and rush of the city.” </p><p>“He remained TRANQUIL while everyone else ran about in confusion.” </p><p>“The TRANQUIL stream became a noisy waterfall when it dropped off the cliff.” </p><p>The noun from TRANQUIL is TRANQUILITY,which means <i class=“def-ital\">peacefulness</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">calmness</i>. </p><p>“The nation’s TRANQUILITY was disturbed by rumors of war.” </p><p>“The TRANQUILITY of the afternoon was suddenly shattered by peals of thunder.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: TRANQUILITY, n. TRANQUILIZER, n.</p>"
    },
    "ANONYMOUS": {
      "word": "ANONYMOUS",
      "phonetic": "(ÔøΩnon'-ÔøΩm:;,s)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">nameless, of unknown name </p><p>ANONYMOUS means “without a name.” The word is used about a person whose name is not known or has not been revealed. </p><p>“The person who sent the gift wishes to remain ANONYMOUS.” </p><p>“The composer of this ancient song is ANONYMOUS.” </p><p>It is also used to mean “of unknown source or origin.” </p><p>“He received an ANONYMOUS phone call telling him where the bomb was located.” </p><p>ANONYMITY is the state of being ANONYMOUS. </p><p>“The author tried to preserve his ANONYMITY by signing a false name to the article.” </p><p>Many people think ANONYMOUS means <i class=“def-ital\">mysterious</i>. An ANONYMOUS person might be mysterious, but for a specific reason: because his name is unknown. </p><p>Other forms ofthe word: ANONYMITY,n.</p>"
    },
    "APPARATUS": {
      "word": "APPARATUS",
      "phonetic": "(ap-ÔøΩra'-tÔøΩs",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">equipment, mechanism </p><p>An APPARATUS is a set of instruments, materials, appliances, or machinery designed to work together for a specific purpose. In the human body it is a group of organs that work together toward one end. </p><p>“The skindiver’s breathing APPARATUS was faulty. The oxygen tank did not connect properly with the nose mask.” </p><p>A fire truck is commonly called a fire APPARATUS because of all the various instruments it has that serve in fighting a fire. </p><p>“The building’s powerful heating APPARATUS consists of a huge furnace and dozens of ducts that carry hot air circulated by fans.”</p>"
    },
    "CAPSIZE": {
      "word": "CAPSIZE",
      "phonetic": "(kap'-slz)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to overturn, upset </p><p>CAPSIZE is used especially about boats. The word means “to turn upside down from a safe to a dangerous position.” A boat can CAPSIZE, or something can CAPSIZE a boat. </p><p>“The little rowboat CAPSIZED in the rough waters of the bay.” </p><p>“A huge wave CAPSIZED the canoe.” </p><p>On the Pretest, <i class=“def-ital\">sink</i> is a common choice as the meaning of CAPSIZE. When a boat CAPSIZES, however, it just turns over in the water. It is in danger of sinking, but it will not necessarily sink.</p>"
    },
    "COLLABORATE": {
      "word": "COLLABORATE",
      "phonetic": "(kÔøΩlab'-ÔøΩrAt)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to work together, cooperate </p><p> Notice the word <i class=“def-ital\">labor</i> in the middle of COLLABORATE. To COLLABORATE is to <i class=“def-ital\">labor</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">work together</i>. </p><p>“Other scientists COLLABORATED with him in carrying out the research.” </p><p>The word is often used about works of literature. </p><p>“The two authors COLLABORATED on a novel.” </p><p>In a special sense, COLLABORATE often is used to mean “to work with an enemy of one’s country.” </p><p>“After the war he was accused of COLLABORATING with the enemy forces.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: COLLABORATION, n. COLLABORATOR, n.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">con-</i> under Prefixes and <i class=“def-ital\">-ate1</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "COMMEND": {
      "word": "COMMEND",
      "phonetic": "(kÔøΩmend')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to praise, recommend; to entrust </p><p>To COMMEND someone is to speak favorably of him, to praise him. </p><p>“I COMMEND you for your honesty.” </p><p>“Bill’s mother COMMENDED his handling of the emergency.” </p><p>Often the word suggests praising someone or something to someone else. In this sense COMMEND is close in meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">recommend</i>. </p><p>“The critic COMMENDED the book to anyone interested in fine writing.” </p><p>In another sense, COMMEND means to <i class=“def-ital\">entrust</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">commit</i>. </p><p>“The dying man COMMENDED his soul to God.” </p><p>The most commonly chosen wrong answer is <i class=“def-ital\">scold</i>, which is just about the opposite of COMMEND. </p><p>Other forms of the word: COMMENDABLE, adj. COMMENDATION, n.</p>"
    }
  },
  "id": "5",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "INTERCEPT the messenger.",
          "answers": [
            "hide",
            "help",
            "replace",
            "tie up",
            "cut off"
          ],
          "word": "INTERCEPT",
          "correct": "cut off"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Used to MEDDLE.",
          "answers": [
            "butt in",
            "drop in",
            "weave",
            "let alone",
            "show off"
          ],
          "word": "MEDDLE",
          "correct": "butt in"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I have MISGIVINGS.",
          "answers": [
            "hopes",
            "doubts",
            "pains",
            "thoughts",
            "needs"
          ],
          "word": "MISGIVING",
          "correct": "doubts"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were MUTE.",
          "answers": [
            "small",
            "loud",
            "silent",
            "useless",
            "empty"
          ],
          "word": "MUTE",
          "correct": "silent"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They will NEGOTIATE with us.",
          "answers": [
            "meet",
            "never speak",
            "become friends",
            "travel",
            "bargain"
          ],
          "word": "NEGOTIATE",
          "correct": "bargain"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Necessary PRECAUTION.",
          "answers": [
            "sign",
            "risk",
            "decision",
            "safeguard",
            "inspection"
          ],
          "word": "PRECAUTION",
          "correct": "safeguard"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Wanted to REFORM them.",
          "answers": [
            "destroy",
            "correct",
            "twist",
            "pray for",
            "protect"
          ],
          "word": "REFORM",
          "correct": "correct"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They will finally RESUME.",
          "answers": [
            "begin again",
            "finish",
            "decide",
            "show up",
            "try"
          ],
          "word": "RESUME",
          "correct": "begin again"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was SERVICEABLE.",
          "answers": [
            "ordinary",
            "impossible",
            "useful",
            "understandable",
            "wonderful"
          ],
          "word": "SERVICEABLE",
          "correct": "useful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Quite TRANQUIL.",
          "answers": [
            "easy",
            "excited",
            "peaceful",
            "secret",
            "grateful"
          ],
          "word": "TRANQUIL",
          "correct": "peaceful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Remained ANONYMOUS.",
          "answers": [
            "dangerous",
            "well known",
            "mysterious",
            "nameless",
            "far away"
          ],
          "word": "ANONYMOUS",
          "correct": "nameless"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Asked for the APPARATUS.",
          "answers": [
            "plan",
            "equipment",
            "container",
            "clothing",
            "assistant"
          ],
          "word": "APPARATUS",
          "correct": "equipment"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To CAPSIZE the boat.",
          "answers": [
            "save",
            "overturn",
            "enlarge",
            "build",
            "sink"
          ],
          "word": "CAPSIZE",
          "correct": "overturn"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We must COLLABORATE.",
          "answers": [
            "work together",
            "give up",
            "fight",
            "meet",
            "become better",
          ],
          "word": "COLLABORATE",
          "correct": "work together"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMMEND them.",
          "answers": [
            "love",
            "scold",
            "protect",
            "select",
            "praise"
          ],
          "word": "COMMEND",
          "correct": "praise"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Can a train be INTERCEPTED?",
          "word": "INTERCEPT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people usually like someone who MEDDLES in their affairs?",
          "word": "MEDDLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would people enjoy having MISGIVINGS?",
          "word": "MISGIVING",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are some deaf people also MUTE?",
          "word": "MUTE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you NEGOTIATE with someone you don't like?",
          "word": "NEGOTIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is wearing a seatbelt in a car a PRECAUTION?",
          "word": "PRECAUTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do all criminals REFORM?",
          "word": "REFORM",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you RESUME an activity that you haven't done for a long time?",
          "word": "RESUME",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a burnt-out light bulb SERVICEABLE?",
          "word": "SERVICEABLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a hurricane TRANQUIL?",
          "word": "TRANQUIL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is William Shakespeare ANONYMOUS?",
          "word": "ANONYMOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is water an APPARATUS?",
          "word": "APPARATUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a boat CAPSIZE with people in it?",
          "word": "CAPSIZE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a person COLLABORATE by himself?",
          "word": "COLLABORATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a person usually be COMMENDED for stealing money?",
          "word": "COMMEND",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "The river INTERCEPTED the city right down the middle.",
          "word": "INTERCEPT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I don't like to MEDDLE, but I think you should listen to my advice.",
          "word": "MEDDLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She always has MISGIVINGS after she agrees to do something difficult.",
          "word": "MISGIVING",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He stood MUTE with wonder before the brilliant painting.",
          "word": "MUTE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The two lawyers NEGOTIATED a settlement in the case, so it never came to trial.",
          "word": "NEGOTIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He received a PRECAUTION from the teacher about his poor behavior.",
          "word": "PRECAUTION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She was in the habit of telling lies, but she REFORMED when she realized the trouble she caused.",
          "word": "REFORM",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I RESUME that everyone will want to come to the beach with us.",
          "word": "RESUME",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The mechanic didn't make the car as good as new, but at least it was SERVICEABLE.",
          "word": "SERVICEABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "After several years of living in the busy city, she longed for the TRANQUILITY of life in the country.",
          "word": "TRANQUIL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He got several ANONYMOUS messages saying he would be killed if he talked to the police.",
          "word": "ANONYMOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They used a complicated APPARATUS to help him breathe after the operation.",
          "word": "APPARATUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They managed to hold onto the boat that had CAPSIZED until they were saved.",
          "word": "CAPSIZE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "No one wanted to COLLABORATE with the enemy soldiers when they conquered the city.",
          "word": "COLLABORATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The principal COMMENDED them for their fine record in school.",
          "word": "COMMEND",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "INTERCEPT",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "interrupt",
            "destroy"
          ],
          "word": "INTERCEPT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MEDDLE",
          "answers": [
            "bother",
            "interfere",
            "threaten"
          ],
          "word": "MEDDLE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MISGIVING",
          "answers": [
            "hatred",
            "worry",
            "suspicion"
          ],
          "word": "MISGIVING",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MUTE",
          "answers": [
            "open",
            "silent",
            "wordless"
          ],
          "word": "MUTE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NEGOTIATE",
          "answers": [
            "expect",
            "discuss",
            "confer"
          ],
          "word": "NEGOTIATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PRECAUTION",
          "answers": [
            "preparation",
            "rejection",
            "care"
          ],
          "word": "PRECAUTION",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REFORM",
          "answers": [
            "improve",
            "repair",
            "approve"
          ],
          "word": "REFORM",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RESUME",
          "answers": [
            "consider",
            "restart",
            "continue"
          ],
          "word": "RESUME",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SERVICEABLE",
          "answers": [
            "satisfactory",
            "wonderful",
            "helpful"
          ],
          "word": "SERVICEABLE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TRANQUIL",
          "answers": [
            "quiet",
            "pretty",
            "gentle"
          ],
          "word": "TRANQUIL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ANONYMOUS",
          "answers": [
            "unknown",
            "unusual",
            "secret"
          ],
          "word": "ANONYMOUS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "APPARATUS",
          "answers": [
            "tool",
            "motor",
            "rock"
          ],
          "word": "APPARATUS",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CAPSIZE",
          "answers": [
            "upset",
            "leak",
            "overturn"
          ],
          "word": "CAPSIZE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COLLABORATE",
          "answers": [
            "laugh",
            "work",
            "join"
          ],
          "word": "COLLABORATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMMEND",
          "answers": [
            "approve",
            "applaud",
            "improve"
          ],
          "word": "COMMEND",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}
